Alexis Johnson

WFB DFVFI OPFR

alexis.johnson052@gmail.com github.com/ajohnson052 219.331.9916 Washington, DC

About Me

As an analytical thinker with a penchant for solving problems, I believe that technology can be used to create positive change. Before I found my niche in web development, I worked as an economist and learned to identify and describe problems. Now, through lines of code, I am excited to be creating solutions.

Experience

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive Program

October 2015 - January 2016

- Built fluency in full-stack web development through completing an intensive threemonth program
- Focused on common best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development

IHS - Economist

October 2014 - October 2015

- Forecasted prices for transportation goods and services using econometric modeling techniques in Eviews
- Contributed written analysis to quarterly IHS publications corresponding with key transportation industries in North America and Europe

University of Pittsburgh — *Teacher's Assistant, Economics Tutor, Tour Guide*August 2010 — April 2014

- Spoke with clarity and confidence about complex topics
- · Adjusted lessons and presentations to the needs of students and campus guests

Volunteering

U.S. Botanic Garden - Educator

November 2015 - present

Casey Trees — Team Leader Candidate

October 2014 - present

Washington English Center - English Tutor

February - April 2015

Worldwide Opportunities on Organic Farms— *Worker for Chilean Fruit Farm* June 2014

Technical Skills

Languages

Ruby Javascript HTML CSS

Frameworks & Libraries

Rails Sinatra RSpec Node.js Express.js Passport.js Handlebars.js Angular.js jQuery

Databases & ORMs

SQL PostgreSQL Active Record MongoDB Mongoose.js

Methodologies

OOP MVC Pattern Agile Development Authentication AJAX

Other

UNIX CLI Git/Github Heroku Trello ERD

Education

University of Pittsburgh

Class of 2014
Full-tuition scholarship
Study abroad
B.S. Economics
B.A. Urban Studies